Finding Aid for Southeast Michigan Council of Governments, Publications, 1949-1992, 1997-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Southeast Michigan Council of Governments, publications 1949-1992, 1997-2010
Southeast Michigan Council of Governments.
3.5 linear feet
98118 Fm 2
Publications of the Southeast Michigan Council of Governments covering various issues facing Southeast Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The SEMCOG publications were acquired as individual items and a part of various accessions.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Southeast Michigan Council of Governments was established in 1968. As described in its mission statement, "SEMCOG solves regional problems by working together with member local governments to improve the quality of life in Southeast Michigan." (from http://www.semcog.org/AboutUs/Overview/index.htm).
The Southeast Michigan Council of Governments publication collection includes both serial and non-serial publications covering various issues facing Southeast Michigan. Also included are publications of a predecessor organization, the Detroit Metropolitan Area Regional Planning Commission. Topics covered include regional planning, population and housing, transportation, water quality, recreation and parks development, and land use planning.
Subjects:
Southeast Michigan Council of Governments.; Detroit Metropolitan Area Regional Planning Commission.; Regional planning--Michigan, Southeastern.; Transportation--Michigan, Southeastern--Planning.; Water quality--Michigan, Southeastern--Planning.; Housing--Michigan, Southeastern.; Detroit Metropolitan Area Regional Planning Commission.
- Serials
  - Annual report 1949-1966
    (Incomplete run, later annual reports are cataloged separately)
    - 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951 (Box 1)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - From TALUS to you
    - April 1969 June 1969 (Box 1)
  - Housing bulletin
    - September 1970, no. 4 (Box 1)
  - The Microscope
    - v.1, no.1 August 1979 (Box 1)
    - v.2, no.1 January 1980 (Box 1)
  - Population and occupied dwelling units...
    - February 1956 (Box 1)
      (Detroit region)
    - July 1958 (Box 1)
      (in the Detroit region)
    - July 1959 (Box 1)
    - July 1962 (Box 1)
    - July 1963 (Box 1)
    - November 1964 (Box 1)
    - July 1965 (Box 1)
    - July 1966 (Box 1)
    - March 1968 (Box 1)
    - July 1968 (Box 1)
    - July 1969 (Box 1)
    - August 1971 (Box 1)
      (First 6 months; dwelling units only; in Southeast Michigan)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
      (First 6 months; dwelling units only)
    - July 1972 (Box 1)
      (in Southeast Michigan)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - 1978 (Box 1)
    - 1992 (Box 1)
  - Regional reporter
    - 1955 (Box 1)
      (no. 14)
    - 1957 (Box 1)
      (no. 20)
    - 1958 (Box 1)
      (no. 24)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
      (no. 38-39)
    - 1962 (Box 1)
      (no. 40)
    - 1965 (Box 1)
      (no. 52-53)
    - 1966 (Box 1)
      (no. 57, 59)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
      (no. 60)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
      (no. 73)
    - November 1972 (Box 1)
  - SEM Council data digest
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
  - SEM Council digest
    - v.2, no.1 January 1973 (Box 1)
  - SEMCOG public notice
    - 2003-2008 (Box 1)
  - Water quality memo
    - No. 17-22 1978 (Box 1)
- Non-serial publications
  - 1949
    - The planning board's job (Box 1)
      (Planning thoughts no. 1)
    - Regional and local planning (Box 1)
      (Planning thoughts no. 2)
  - 1951
    - Industrial decentralization, Detroit region 1940-1950 (projection to 1970), by Paul M. Reid (Box 1)
  - 1955
    - Home location pattern of industrial workers in the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - Progress report--waterfront land use plan (Box 1)
  - 1956
    - Suburban shopping centers Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1957
    - Master planning and the law (Box 1)
  - 1958
    - Features of industrial location in the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - Progress in regional planning (Box 1)
  - 1959
    - 1958 land use in the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - Employment of women in the Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1960
    - Home survey of regional recreation activities
      - Part III: Recreation in the Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1961
    - Off-rail industrial lands plan for the Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1962
    - Conference papers: 12th annual planning conference (Box 1)
      (Recreational planning conference papers: title page missing)
  - 1963
    - 1970-1980 population projections in the Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1964
    - Detroit region dwelling unit report based on residential units authorized (Box 1)
    - Study design for a comprehensive transportation and land use program for the Detroit region (Box 1)
  - 1965
    - 1964 Residential construction in the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - Conference papers: 15 annual planning conference (Box 1)
  - 1966
    - Digest of existing and proposed state and federal laws related to regional planning in Southeast Michigan (Box 1)
    - Flood plains reconnaissance study for the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - Regional planning, 1965-66 (Box 1)
  - 1967
    - Conference papers: 16th annual planning conference (Box 1)
    - Environmental studies: design resources technical report (Box 1)
    - Environmental studies: natural resources technical report (Box 1)
    - Guidelines for levels of function and responsibility for public outdoor recreation in Southeast Michigan (Box 1)
    - Living patterns and attitudes in the Detroit region technical report (Box 1)
    - Planning activity in the Detroit Region, January 1, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Residential construction in the Detroit region, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Residential land development in the Detroit region, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - 1968
    - A profile of Southeastern Michigan TALUS data (Box 1)
    - TALUS and tomorrow (Box 1)
  - 1969
    - Growth, change... and a choice for 1990 preliminary plan, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 1970
    - 1970 SEMCOG work program & budget (Box 1)
    - Inventory of drug abuse programs: a guide to resources... (Box 1)
    - Planning activity in the Detroit region (Box 1)
    - State-local relations in Southeast Michigan (Box 1)
  - 1971
    - Public high school districts in Southeast Michigan: Selected financial data (Box 1)
    - Survey of manufactured housing available to Southeast Michigan (Box 1)
  - 1972
    - 1970 census data, 1st count (Box 1)
    - Regional publications and planning materials (Box 1)
  - 1973 (Box 2)
    - Housing Southeast Michigan: a plan and program (Box 2)
    - Mobil home parks and sites in Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
    - Regional publications and planning materials (Box 2)
    - Solid waste study (Box 2)
  - 1974
    - 1990 regional recreation and open space plan for Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
    - Draft summary statement for the proposed 1990 transportation plan for the Southeast Michigan region (Box 2)
    - Model flood plain, watercourse and wetland ordinance for townships (Box 2)
    - Transportation 1990 (Box 2)
  - 1975
    - Energy and the regional transportation plan: a multi-modal energy analysis: draft (Box 2)
    - Procedures to evaluate the consistency of the regional transportation plan with the state implementation plan: draft (Box 2)
    - Transportation: an integrated highway-transit plan for Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
  - 1976
    - Clean water for Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
    - Perspective on progress (Box 2)
    - Precipitation in Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
    - Social impacts of transportation: regional analysis of transportation needs of the disadvantaged: draft (Box 2)
      (Transportation working paper, no. 30)
    - Water quality in Southeast Michigan: an annotated bibliography (Box 2)
  - 1977
    - Downriver truck study by Wilbur Smith and Associates (Box 2)
    - Inland lake management concerns for Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
      (Environmental background paper, no. 26)
    - Regional bikeway system plan: draft, 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - Water quality management plan for Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
  - 1978
    - Clinton River water quality (Box 2)
      (Water quality memo, no. 21-22)
    - Description of proposed trip production model for home-based motor vehicle person trips (Box 2)
    - Federal grant review process in Southeast Michigan (Box 2)
      (revised March 1978)
    - Huron River water quality (Box 2)
      (Water quality memo, no. 19-20)
    - Regional bikeway policy plan: an element of the regional transportation plan for the Southeast Michigan region (Box 2)
    - Regional transportation plan for Southeast Michigan: Highway and transit elements (Box 2)
      (amended March 1978)
    - River Rouge water quality (Box 2)
      (Water quality memo, no. 17-18)
    - Water quality in Southeast Michigan: introduction (Box 2)
    - Water quality management plan for Southeast Michigan: environmental assessment summary: draft (Box 2)
  - 1979
    - Executive summary for the regional transportation systems management plan: draft (Box 2)
  - 1980 (Box 3)
    - Clean air, transportation and you (Box 3)
    - Economic development in southeast Michigan: a profile and inventory (Box 3)
    - Southeast Michigan: a profile of the region (Box 3)
    - The transition plan for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
  - 1981
    - Conservation easements: tax incentives for private open space preservation (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 6)
    - Detention basin maintenance: program needs and financing options (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 3)
    - Effective stormwater management programs: case studies of local government experiences in Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Performance zoning: an innovative approach to water quality protection and land use regulation (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 7)
    - Protecting water quality through cluster development: financial incentives and community benefits (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 5)
    - Septic system management by local governments: planning, regulation, and maintenance (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 4)
    - Stormwater runoff control through natural drainage: cost savings and environmental benefits (Box 3)
      (Technical bulletin, no. 2)
  - 1982
    - Intergovernmental cooperative arrangements: exploring opportunities (Box 3)
    - Social and economic impacts of toxic waste sites: the experience of Rose and Springfield Townships: summary of major findings (Box 3)
  - 1984
    - Final responsiveness summary: North Huron Valley-Rouge Valley wastewater control system preliminary engineering report (Box 3)
    - Major economic activity concentrations in Southeast Michigan: a supplement to the map, "Major economic activity in Southeast Michigan" (Box 3)
  - 1985
    - SEMCOG: a guide (Box 3)
    - Southeast Michigan: a regional profile (Box 3)
  - 1987
    - Public transportation needs and finance assessment for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
  - 1988
    - Public transportation element of the year 2005 regional transportation plan: a technical report (Box 3)
  - 1989
    - Southeast Michigan traffic crash profile (Box 3)
  - 1990
    - Regional traffic safety policies for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
      (draft)
    - Regional traffic safety policies for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Tax incentives/tax abatements in Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
  - 1991
    - The "Business as usual" trend future: the data base (Box 3)
    - Economy 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #4)
    - Education reforms: issues and recommendations (Box 3)
    - The environment, 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #1)
    - Management & governance 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #6)
    - Public finance 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #5)
    - Regional development initiative: final report of the RDI Oversight Committee (Box 3)
    - Regional development initiative: summary of workshop #1, the environment (Box 3)
    - Regional development initiative: summary of workshop #4, economy (Box 3)
    - Regional development initiative: summary of workshop #6, management & governance (Box 3)
    - Social impacts: crime, race, education 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #2)
    - Southeast Michigan regional aviation system plan: evaluation of alternative systems: draft (Box 3)
      (Working paper, no. 5)
    - Transportation 1990/2010 (Box 3)
      (Regional development initiative briefing paper #3)
  - 1992
    - Southeast Michigan regional aviation system plan technical report (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
      (flyers and clippings)
  - 1997
    - 2020 regional Southeast Michigan regional transportation plan summary (Box 3)
  - 1999
    - Best practices for sustainable development (Box 3)
    - Transportation 2000 and beyond" a visioning process (Box 3)
  - 2000
    - Regional transit: what's its future? (Box 3)
    - Transportation acronyms and glossary (Box 3)
  - 2001
    - Citizens' guide to transportation planning in Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Draft FY 2002-2004 transportation improvement program for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Improving transit in Southeast Michigan, July 2001 draft (Box 3)
    - Improving transit in Southeast Michigan: a framework for action (Box 3)
    - Improving transit in Southeast Michigan: a framework for action summary (Box 3)
    - Major transportation funding programs available ... (Box 3)
    - Regional transit options (Box 3)
  - 2002
    - Regional transportation opinion survey: reporting the results (Box 3)
  - 2003
    - 2002 Southeast Michigan traffic crash facts (Box 3)
    - 2030 regional transportation plan: needs, revenues, and priorities (Box 3)
    - Annual work program completion report for fiscal year 2002-2003 (Box 3)
    - Commuting in Southeast Michigan, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Employment change by community, Southeast Michigan, 1999-2002 (Box 3)
    - Financing joint public ventures: alternatives and consequences) (Box 3)
    - Fiscal capacity of Southeast Michigan communities: taxable value and its implications (Box 3)
    - Funding resources for investing in the transportation system of Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Intergovernmental cooperation: a background paper (Box 3)
    - Intergovernmental cooperation: strategies for overcoming political barriers) (Box 3)
    - MDOT freeway courtesy patrol in Southeast Michigan: 2002 evaluation report (Box 3)
    - Michigan's legal tools for cooperative arrangements (Box 3)
    - Population and households in Southeast Michigan, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
    - SEMCOG's proposal for moving forward on the Land Use Leadership Council's recommendations (Box 3)
  - 2004
    - 2030 regional transportation plan for Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - 2030 regional transportation plan for Southeast Michigan: project list (Box 3)
    - 2030 regional transportation plan for Southeast Michigan: regional transportation needs (Box 3)
    - Conditional land transfer act: research, reflections, and policy recommendations (Box 3)
    - Intergovernmental cooperation: studies in Southeast Michigan (Box 3)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Livingston County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Macomb County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Monroe County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Oakland County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, regional summary, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, St. Clair County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Washtenaw County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Land use in Southeast Michigan, Wayne County, 1990-2000 (Box 4)
    - Migration and its impact on Southeast Michigan, 1990-2003 (Box 4)
    - Nonresidential development in Southeast Michigan, summary 2003 (Box 4)
    - Population and households in Southeast Michigan, 2000-2004 (Box 4)
    - Profile of I-275 corridor communities: for the University of Michigan and Urban Land Institute's 18th annual real estate forum (Box 4)
    - Regional impact review proposed crosswinds communities planned community development Milan Township, Michigan (Box 4)
    - SEMCOG rain gauge network 2003 annual report (Box 4)
    - Sensitivity analysis of EPA's new mobile model (Box 4)
  - 2005
    - Annual work program completion report for fiscal year 2004-2005 (Box 4)
    - Citizens' guide to transportation planning in Southeast Michigan (Box 4)
    - Population and households in Southeast Michigan, 2000-2005 (Box 4)
    - Profile of Detroit beyond the Super Bowl (Box 4)
    - Residential construction in Southeast Michigan, 2004 (Box 4)
    - SEMCOG annual operating budget and work program summary: fiscal year ending June 30, 2006 (Box 4)
    - SEMCOG rain gauge network January-June 2005 report (Box 4)
    - State and local government financing of essential services with user fees (Box 4)
    - Transit Impediments Committee Report (Box 4)
  - 2006
    - 2000 Southeast Michigan traffic crash facts (Box 4)
    - 2005 Southeast Michigan traffic crash facts (Box 4)
    - Asset management road condition report, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Building stronger communities: the community development block grant in Michigan (Box 4)
    - Funding resources for investing in the transportation system of Southeast Michigan, 2006 (Box 4)
    - MDOT freeway courtesy patrol in Southeast Michigan: 2005 evaluation report (Box 4)
    - Population and households in Southeast Michigan, 2000-2006 (Box 4)
    - Residential construction in Southeast Michigan, 2005 (Box 4)
  - 2007
    - American community survey profile Michigan, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Regional Concept of Transportation Operations (RCTO) final report: Southeast Michigan experience (Box 4)
    - Regional Concept of Transportation Operations (RCTO) for Southeast Michigan (Box 4)
  - 2008
    - Asset management road condition report, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Asset management road condition report, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Fiscal capacity of Southeast Michigan communities: taxable value and its implications, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Investment in reducing combined sewer overflows pays dividends (Box 4)
    - Passenger vehicles and air pollution: a profile of Southeast Michigan's fleet (Box 4)
    - Population and households in Southeast Michigan, 2000-2008 (Box 4)
    - Redevelopment capacity in the city of Detroit (Box 4)
    - Status of bridges in Southeast Michigan. 2006 (Box 4)
  - 2009
    - MDOT freeway courtesy patrol in Southeast Michigan: FY 2008 evaluation report (Box 4)
    - Nonresidential development activity in Southeast Michigan, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Residential construction in Southeast Michigan. 2008 (Box 4)
    - SEMCOG 2035 forecast population by age group by school district (Box 4)
  - 2010
    - Creating a sustainable infrastructure system in Southeast Michigan (Box 4)
    - Increasing jobs and prosperity in Southeast Michigan (Box 4)
  - Miscellanea (Box 4)